<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<card type="2" cost="6" date="">
    <title>Astronaut</title>
    <shortDescription>+1 card, +1 action, +1 buy, +2 coins</shortDescription>
    <longDescription>NASA planners invented the term extra-vehicular activity in the early 1960s for the Apollo program to land men on the Moon, because the astronauts would leave the  spacecraft to collect lunar material samples and deploy scientific  experiments. To support this, and other Apollo objectives, the Gemini program was spun off to develop the capability for astronauts to work outside a two-man Earth orbiting spacecraft.The first American spacewalk was performed on June 3, 1965, by Edward H. White, II from the second manned Gemini flight, Gemini 4, for 21 minutes, on a 25-foot (7.6'm) tether. White was the first to control his motion in space with a Hand-Held Maneuvering Unit, which worked well but only carried enough propellant for 20 seconds. No EVAs were planned on the next three Gemini flights. The next EVA was planned to be made by David Scott on Gemini 8,  but that mission had to be aborted due to a critical spacecraft  malfunction before the EVA could be conducted. Astronauts on the next  three Gemini flights (Eugene Cernan, Michael Collins, and Richard Gordon), performed several EVAs, but none was able to successfully work for long periods outside the spacecraft without tiring and overheating. Finally, on November 13, 1966, Edwin ""Buzz"" Aldrin became the first to successfully work in space without tiring, on the Gemini 12 last flight. Aldrin worked outside the spacecraft for 2 hours and 6  minutes, in addition to two stand-up EVAs in the spacecraft hatch for an additional 3 hours and 24 minutes. Aldrin's interest in scuba diving inspired the use of underwater EVA training to simulate weightlessness, which has been used ever since to allow astronauts to practice techniques of avoiding wasted muscle energy. The first EVA on the lunar surface was performed by Americans Neil Armstrong and Buz  Aldrin on July 21, 1969 (UTC), after the Apollo 11  Moon landing. This first Moon walk lasted 2 hours, 36 minutes. A total  of fifteen Moon walks were performed by members of six Apollo crews,  including Charles ""Pete"" Conrad, Alan Bean, Alan Shepard, Edgar Mitchell, David Scott, James Irwin, John Young, Charles Duke, Eugene ""Gene"" Cernan, and Dr. Harrison ""Jack"" Schmitt. Cernan was the last Apollo astronaut to step off the surface of the Moon.Charles Duke with a hammer on the lunar surface.The first EVA in deep space was made on August 5, 1971, by American Al Worden, to retrieve a film and data recording canister from the Apollo 15 Service Module on the return trip from the Moon. Worden was assisted by James Irwin,  doing a standup EVA in the Command Module hatch. This was repeated by Ken Mattingly and Charles Duke on Apollo 16 and by Ronald Evans and Harrison Schmitt on Apollo 17.[4] The first EVA repairs of a spacecraft were made by Charles ""Pete"" Conrad, Joseph Kerwin, and Paul J. Weitz on May 26, June 7, and June 19, 1973, on the Skylab 2 mission. They rescued the functionality of the launch-damaged Skylab space station by freeing a stuck solar panel, deploying a solar heating shield, and freeing a stuck circuit breaker relay. The Skylab 2 crew made three EVAs, and a total of ten EVAs were  made by the three Skylab crews.They found that activities in weightlessness required about 2 1/2 times the duration as on Earth because many astronauts suffered spacesickness early in their flights.After Skylab, no more EVAs were made by the United States until the advent of the Space Shuttle program in the early 1980s. In this period, the Soviets resumed EVAs, making four from the Salyut 6 and Salyut 7 space stations between December 20, 1977, and July 30, 1982.</longDescription>
    <filename>astronaut</filename>
    <victoryPoints></victoryPoints>
<moreActions count="1" />
<moreCards count="1" />
<moreCoins count="2" />
<moreBuys count="1" />
</card>