<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<card type="2" cost="5" date="">
    <title>Kennedy's Speech</title>
    <shortDescription>+4 cards, +1 buy, each other player draws a card</shortDescription>
    <longDescription>Kennedy Space Center was created for the Apollo manned lunar landing program, and has evolved to meet the changing needs of America's manned space  program. Although such flights are currently on hiatus, KSC continues to manage and operate unmanned rocket launch facilities for the U.S. government's civilian space program from three pads at the adjoining Cape Canaveral Air Force Station. Its Vehicle Assembly Building (VAB) is the fourth-largest structure in the world by volume, and was the largest when completed in 1965. At NASA's creation in 1958, its launch operation was originally known as the Launch Operations Directorate (LOD), reporting to the Marshall Space Flight Center in Alabama. This consisted of a few buildings in the Industrial Area of Cape Canaveral Missile Test Annex, later known as Cape Canaveral Air Force Station. Cape Canaveral Air Force Station (CCAFS) is an installation of the United States Air Force Space Command's 45th Space Wing, headquartered at nearby Patrick Air Force Base. Located on Cape Canaveral in the state of Florida, CCAFS is the primary launch head of America's Eastern Range with four launch pads currently active. Popularly known as ""Cape Kennedy"" from 1963 to 1973, and as ""Cape Canaveral"" from 1949 to 1963  and from 1973 to the present, the facility is south-southeast of NASA's Kennedy Space Center on adjacent Merritt Island, with the two linked by bridges and causeways. The Cape Canaveral AFS Skid Strip provides a 10,000-foot (3,000'm) runway[6] close to the launch complexes for military airlift aircraft delivering heavy and outsized payloads to the Cape. Many major American space exploration ""firsts"" were launched from CCAFS, including the first U.S. Earth satellite (1958), first U.S. astronaut (1961), first U.S. astronaut in orbit (1962), first two-man U.S. spacecraft (1965), first U.S. unmanned lunar landing (1966), and first three-man U.S. spacecraft (1968). It was also the launch site for the first spacecraft to ever fly past the other planets in the Solar System (1962'1977), the first spacecraft to orbit Mars (1971) and roam its surface (1996), the first American spacecraft to orbit and land on Venus (1978), the first spacecraft to orbit Saturn (2004), and to orbit Mercury (2011).</longDescription>
    <filename>jfkspeech</filename>
    <victoryPoints></victoryPoints>
<moreCards count="4" />
<moreBuys count="1" />
</card>